Azat Serikov

Front-end Engineer

Location: Nur-Sultan, Kazakhstan Email: <u>azatsdev@gmail.com</u> Github: <u>https://github.com/azat-s</u> Website: <u>https://azats.dev</u>

ABOUT

I am a front-end developer specializing in high-performance web applications. I have developed and maintained a wide range of websites including GIS services, CRM systems, landing pages, blogs, and other web applications. What I lack in experience, I make up for in flexibility, adaptability and quick learning. In my spare time I enjoy automating daily tasks with Python scripts, tinkering with my customized code editor, and trying out new technologies.

KEY SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Redux
- CSS (BEM)

- Responsive layout
- Git
- Bash
- Python
- Node.js

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

P2P Validator, Moscow, Russia - Front-end Developer

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop secure and performant applications for interacting with cryptocurrencies and blockchains
- Build responsive cross-browser landing pages, optimize SEO, and manage Google Analytics and mailing-list integrations
- Enhance and maintain a complex cryptocurrency-portfolio dashboard
- Customize and improve themes for blog websites
- Write automated tests, perform quality assessment
- Contribute to open-source projects and submit issues
- Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Material UI, styled-components, Redux, Redux Saga, Web3, Ghost CMS, Docker

IBEC Systems, Almaty, KZ - Front-end Developer

JAN 2020 - SEP 2020

- Worked on a complex UI for a CRM system: extended functionality; added modules; performed code refactoring, UX/UI optimization, performance profiling; and wrote automated tests
- Built a reusable-component library that was used across multiple CRM services
- Proposed a peer code review practice that was adopted and successfully implemented
- Learned design patterns for a large-scale React application: authentication, routing, global state management, code splitting, styling, component library, communication with backend
- Learned the intricacies of effective communication with business clients and project management staff
- Developed essential skills for working in agile environment, pair programming and problem solving
- Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Redux, Redux Saga, Material UI

Tamur Ltd., Nur-Sultan, KZ - Web Developer

MAY 2019 - DEC 2019

- Worked on an interactive cadastral map and introduced features such as calculating routes and areas, displaying dynamic diagrams and other manipulations and interactions with web-based geographic maps
- Learned a great deal about GIS, geographic coordinate systems, cartography and time zones
- Learned the core principles for efficient client-server communication via RESTful API architecture
- Worked with a senior engineer with 20+ years of experience in software development, who provided mentorship and guidance
- Technologies: React.js, styled-components, OpenLayers, ArcGIS,

FORMAL EDUCATION

Sh. Ualikhanov State University, Kokshetau - Bachelor

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Translation & Interpretation, English

LANGUAGES

- Russian native
- English proficient (Certified: IELTS Band 8, June 2020)